{
  "heading": "Converting Unlike fractions to like fractions Addition and subtraction.",
  "topics": [
    {
      "heading": "Converting Unlike fractions to like fractions Addition and subtraction.",
      "questions": [
        {
            "questionNo": 1,
            "question": "During the celebration preparations, one group of villagers collected 3/8 of the flowers for the decorations, while another group collected 6/13 of the flowers. What are the equivalent fractions of these amounts when converted to like fractions?",
            "options": [
                "39/104 and 48/104",
                "37/104 and 45/104",
                "42/104 and 47/104",
                "40/104 and 48/104"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 2,
            "question": "For the village square decoration, one group of villagers painted 1/6 of the area in blue, and another group painted 1/17 in green. What fraction of the square is painted by both groups together?",
            "options": [
                "29/120",
                "23/102",
                "22/103",
                "21/105"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 3,
            "question": "During the grand feast, one group of villagers used 2/20 of the available chairs, but another group used 1/50. What is the exact difference between the fractions of chairs used by the two groups?",
            "options": [
                "80/1000",
                "70/1000",
                "50/1000",
                "20/1000"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 4,
            "question": "The villagers of Fractionville were preparing drinks for the feast. One group mixed 4/11 of orange juice, and another group mixed 2/9 of apple juice. What are the equivalent fractions of these amounts when converted to like fractions?",
            "options": [
                "35/95 and 25/95",
                "99/36 and 99/22",
                "33/91 and 22/91",
                "36/99 and 22/99"
            ],
            "answer": 3
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 5,
            "question": "For the dessert table, one chef-prepared 1/4 of a cake, and another chef prepared 6/7 of a cake. What are the equivalent fractions for these amounts when converted to like fractions?",
            "options": [
                "6/28 and 20/28",
                "7/28 and 22/28",
                "7/28 and 24/28",
                "7/28 and 25/28"
            ],
            "answer": 2
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 6,
            "question": "During the celebration, one team served 2/8 of a cake, and another team served 5/6 of a cake. What is the total fraction of cake served during the celebration?",
            "options": [
                "25/24",
                "52/48",
                "47/54",
                "48/52"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 7,
            "question": "The villagers wanted to create flower arrangements. They used 8/9 of a garland for roses and 7/8 of another garland for lilies. What is the total fraction of garlands used for the arrangements?",
            "options": [
                "147/72",
                "127/72",
                "72/127",
                "45/127"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 8,
            "question": "The villagers wanted to decorate the feast hall with banners. One group had 3/14 of a banner with sunflowers, and another group had 1/11 with tulips. What are the like fractions for these amounts?",
            "options": [
                "66/152 and 13/152",
                "31/154 and 14/154",
                "33/154 and 14/154",
                "35/152 and 14/152"
            ],
            "answer": 2
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 9,
            "question": "During the feast preparations, the villagers collected 7/10 of the flowers for decorations, and another group collected 8/15. What are the equivalent fractions of these amounts when converted to like fractions?",
            "options": [
                "105/150 and 80/150",
                "105/140 and 81/140",
                "151/150 and 80/150",
                "151/140 and 81/140"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 10,
            "question": "During the feast preparations, one group of villagers had 15/9 of a fruit basket filled with apples, and another group had 15/6 filled with oranges. What is the total fraction of fruits when these amounts are added together?",
            "options": [
                "252/58",
                "295/55",
                "255/84",
                "225/54"
            ],
            "answer": 3
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 11,
            "question": "During the feast preparations, one team gathered 10/12 of the apples for the pie, while another team collected 12/15 of the apples. What are the equivalent fractions of these amounts when converted to like fractions?",
            "options": [
                "140/180 and 90/180",
                "150/180 and 80/180",
                "130/180 and 70/180",
                "140/180 and 60/180"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 12,
            "question": "During the feast, one group of villagers used 12/8 of the available chairs, and another group used 3/4. What is the difference between the fractions of chairs used by the two groups?",
            "options": [
                "24/31",
                "24/32",
                "42/31",
                "42/32"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 13,
            "question": "For the grand feast, the villagers baked cakes. One baker made 23/60 of a cake, and another baker made 12/50 of a cake. What are the equivalent fractions for these amounts when converted to like fractions?",
            "options": [
                "1105/3000 and 702/3000",
                "1150/3000 and 720/3000",
                "1105/3000 and 720/3000",
                "1140/3000 and 700/3000"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 14,
            "question": "During the celebration, one group of villagers used 25/50 of the available plates, and another group used 13/30. What is the difference between the fractions of plates used by the two groups?",
            "options": [
                "100/1500",
                "101/1150",
                "120/1500",
                "90/1150"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 15,
            "question": "For the celebration, one team prepared 9/13 of the decorations, and another team prepared 9/16. What is the difference between the fractions of decorations prepared by the two teams?",
            "options": [
                "27/208",
                "17/106",
                "23/106",
                "24/208"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 16,
            "question": "During the feast preparations, the villagers gathered 19/7 of the apples, and another group gathered 17/21 of the oranges. What is the total fraction of fruits gathered in Fractionville?",
            "options": [
                "518/147",
                "418/157",
                "519/147",
                "318/157"
            ],
            "answer": 0
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 17,
            "question": "During the feast preparations, the villagers collected 3/8 of the flowers for one arrangement and 5/12 of the flowers for another arrangement. What are the equivalent fractions of these amounts of flowers when converted to like fractions?",
            "options": [
                "36/96 and 40/94",
                "36/96 and 40/96",
                "36/32 and 40/32",
                "39/24 and 40/24"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 18,
            "question": "During the celebration in Fractionville, one group of villagers harvested 11/12 of the total corn, while another group harvested 16/17. What are the equivalent fractions of these amounts when converted to like fractions?",
            "options": [
                "187/202 and 192/202",
                "167/204 and 172/204",
                "167/202 and 192/202",
                "187/204 and 192/204"
            ],
            "answer": 3
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 19,
            "question": "During the feast preparations, the villagers collected 40/50 of the fruits for the baskets but used only 25/40. What is the difference between the fractions of fruits collected and used?",
            "options": [
                "550/2000",
                "350/2000",
                "250/2000",
                "450/2000"
            ],
            "answer": 1
        },
        {
            "questionNo": 20,
            "question": "For the feast's dessert table, one baker made 18/7 of a pie, and another baker made 25/4 of a cake. What are the equivalent fractions for these amounts when converted to like fractions?",
            "options": [
                "76/28 and 150/28",
                "71/28 and 145/28",
                "72/28 and 175/28",
                "17/28 and 165/28"
            ],
            "answer": 2
        }
    ]
    
    
    }
  ]
}
